YUNUS IBRAHIM

South Portland, ME 04106

Phone: 207 420 6078 | Email: hireme@yunusibrahim.me

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yunus-ibrahim | **GitHub:** https://github.com/Yunusib12 |

Portfolio: https://yunusibrahim.me

SUMMARY

Dedicated and efficient Full Stack Developer with a background in Network and System Administration and educated through the University of New Hampshire Coding Bootcamp. Through developed skills, am able to create an intuitive user experience through responsive web designs. Enjoy learning new skills, collaborating and problem solving.

Fluent in English, French, Swahili, and Kirundi.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

CSS3, HTML5, Materialize, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, React, Angular, VB.Net, PHP, Node.js, Express.js, Apache, SQL, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, Amazon Web Services, GitHub, Heroku, Trello, Asana.

PROJECTS

FoodSta | https://github.com/Yunusib12/Foodsta.git | https://deliciousfoodsta.com

- Allows users to search for nearby restaurants, cuisines and meals
- Users can create accounts and post reviews about their meals
- User can use the Authentication and Validation through Passport.JS, the User can save their chart(s) since it is securely held within our MySQL database.
- Tools used: Angular, HTML5/SCSS, AWS S3, Auth0, Express, Sequelize, Node.js, Google Places API
- **Type:** Full Stack

Charted | https://github.com/Yunusib12/Charted.git | https://charted-v1-0.herokuapp.com/

- Allows farmers and ranchers struggling to decipher their livestock and / or crop performance
- With Charted, a farmer / rancher can upload a .CSV file for on-demand field management.
- Tools used: JavaScript, PassportJS, ChartJS, MySQL, Sequelize, NodeJS, ExpressJS, bcryptjs, dotenv. multer
- Type: Full Stack

Google Book | https://github.com/Yunusib12/rg-books.git | https://reactgbook.herokuapp.com/

- A Single Page Application guery and display books based on user searches
- A full MERN stack application allows users to save books to a database to refer to later.
- Tools used: Bootstrap, Express, Node.is, React, MongoDB, Heroku, Socket.io
- Type: Full Stack

EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer Pierce Promotion

2016 - 2018

Portland,

Maine

Design, develop, and unit test applications in accordance with established standards, implemented web applications using Visual Basic.Net. Participated in peer-reviews of solution designs and related code. *Key Accomplishments:*

- Re-designed most their application to be responsive
- Helped implement box file upload in their applications

Web Designer/ Computer Lab Assistant Portland Adult Education

2015 - 2016

Portland. Maine

Design, develop, and implemented their web site.

Key Accomplishments:

- Design and implement website for NMRC (www.nmrcmaine.org)
- Assist 250 students speaking more than 7 languages using different English learning websites

EDUCATION

Coding Bootcamp Certificate: University of New Hampshire

June 2019 - December 2019

- A 24-week intensive technical program focused on developing skills in HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express and React

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Sciences: University of Kinshasa, Republic Democratic of Congo 2011